hello and welcome to the 23rd tutorial
on how to program NG script 2 so I can't
actually enter my server anymore because
I'm not sure why probably because maybe
the subscription ended well I just can't
enter it anymore it's not there it's
gone and that's not a good thing because
I can't program NG script 2 unless I go
to another server and all the things on
that server are gone well I kind of got
rid of a lot of things when I started
this series but all of it's always back
on my computer anyway but all the things
that I made during the tutorials was um
is now gone but I think that's the
problem with gript too is that you know
you're kind of forced to have a server
or or get hired on a server to program
it and you can't like there's no level
editor like there is for gript 1 I don't
like that I wish um Stefan or whoever
does all that would make a level level
editor for gript 2 but I don't think
it's going to
happen so it's not a good thing because
for one to learn gript 2 you're going to
need to join a server or buy a server
because you need to practice to learn it
and no one's going to hire you unless
you know it is that right so unless you
join some very new server who that's
desperate for everyone to come I don't
think it's possible to really learn it
unless you buy it and I don't want to
pay I don't want to pay that much money
to have a server again so yeah I'm gonna
make make this tutorial in the gript one
level editor and I won't be able to run
it but I'm going to explain through it
and hopefully you understand it okay so
this is in a level MPC in a level now at
the top I have function oncreated and I
put the set shape this is needed in an
NPC if you want to use Trigger action on
the NPC this is not needed for
weapons Trigger action is a
new command I'm going to teach you now
just ignore this part right now okay so
under client side I have a function
function on was hit where if I slash the
MPC then whatever is in these brackets
will run okay so Trigger
action trigger action is a command
that allows variables or something to on
client side to be sent over to server
side and this is very useful you can
also send over variables and all that
you probably will understand the
usefulness of it in this tutorial since
I won't be able to show it but I'll try
to explain now trigger Trigger action
is is for NPCs trigger well I guess can
also be used in weapons but trigger
server
is a different command and it is used in
weapons if you want to look that up on
the girl all Wiki or actually that's the
best place to look it up then I would do
that if you want to learn it because
it's very useful but I'm going to use
Trigger action which is pretty much the
same thing as trigger server and it does
the same thing okay so on the first two
variables I specify the position it
doesn't really matter since we're just
going to be sending over
nothing we're just going to have it go
to this line to this function and run it
we don't really want to send anything
anything over if we want to send
something over we have to put it after
the name the name is important kind of
on the function that you want to send it
to you have to have on action set level
which I have here this is called set
level and this function is called set
level so anyway the fourth parameter
here is what gets sent over to this
function right here which you can stop
ignoring now um if we put
something like temp. high we would have
to have it here temp. High equal
5 then if we want to send that over we
can just put any variable name here VAR
and then it's here just like sending
over variables to any other
function okay but I'm going to put null
which is the same thing as putting
nothing okay so I'm just going to go to
this function here after this is run ran
or whatever it goes to this function
and it runs what's in these parentheses
you can put anything there you can put
player that chat equals whatever but
it's always going to it's going to be on
server side and everybody on the server
is going to see it or at least in that's
around the player so they can see it
okay and this is the second part of the
tutorial I'm going to
teach this is a for special for
Loop
four actually I'm going to write it out
again four
temp. PL or whatever variable we want
VAR um 7 let's just put PL then we put a
colon the two dots with the two dots and
we put a an an array let's put all
players all players is a special type of
of array that holds all the
players on the server and I'll show you
what that will do in a second you don't
really you don't have to have these
after it it's possible but we don't need
that let's put
some
brackets now so what this is going to do
is it's going to Loop through all of the
players on the
server and it's and nothing's going to
happen it's going to quit the for Loop
and then continue on into
nothingness
okay so what we're going to do here is
we're going to put PL
which is the variable
here then put dot chat is equal
to
hello okay this is may be a bit
confusing to understand so what this is
doing is it's looping through all the
players on the server and specifying
them with this temp dot variable now
when it finds a player on the server
which is going to be pretty much every
person here it's G to
run this command once what's going to
run the command for everyone and it's
making everybody on the server say
hello and we're doing this by putting
PL which is here and is a variable for
the player the specific player. chat is
equal to hello you may not understand
this but if you try it you'll get it so
it's making everybody on the server say
hello including you we can also put this
if
player do um Nick is equal
to
um killer it's a manly name then pl.
chat is equal to hello so it's going to
Loop through everybody on the server and
if it finds someone oh I don't want to
put player I want to put PL I'm sorry
and if it finds someone there whose name
is killer it's going to make them say
hello
we can also do this
PL
dot dur is equal to one this will make
everybody on the server face to the left
we can put anything we want we can make
it so everybody warps to a level on the
server we can make it so
that yeah we can do a lot of things and
we don't have to just put on all players
we can put some other stuff anyway that
concludes this tutorial which may be the
final tutorial I'm ever going to make on
gript 2
and I hope you understand those two
things Trigger action and these special
for loops and how to Loop through
everybody on the server and there and
you can also do trigger server which is
for like weapons but you can look up go
to the grow Wiki and look at that
because I can't show you anymore because
my server is not up anymore and I don't
want to pay for it so by and I hope I
taught you a lot about gript 2 and you
can use it because it's a really fun
language I just wish it was a bit more
accessible to new people and people who
want it for free